<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Melanie Cebula&#39;s Blog</title>
		<link>http://melaniecebula.github.io/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Melanie Cebula&#39;s Blog</description>
		<generator>Hugo 0.53 -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en</language>
		<managingEditor>melaniecebula.bass@gmail.com (Melanie Cebula)</managingEditor>
		<webMaster>melaniecebula.bass@gmail.com (Melanie Cebula)</webMaster>
		<copyright>Melanie Cebula — All rights reserved.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 18:18:25 -0800</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="http://melaniecebula.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Starting a Blog</title>
			<link>http://melaniecebula.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 18:18:25 -0800</pubDate>
			<author>melaniecebula.bass@gmail.com (Melanie Cebula)</author>
			<guid>http://melaniecebula.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;In 2018 I decided to engage more with the larger technical community. I knew I
wanted to speak at a technical conference, but I had zero experience finding
conferences, filling out
abstracts, and submitting before CFPs close. I gave a first talk at FutureStack 2017,
but that was a bit different since it was a vendor conference and Airbnb was
invited to speak there. Also a manager signed me up before telling me about it
(thanks Joey!), so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t planned. So I started submitting proposals in the
middle of summer 2018. I got a
rejection, and three acceptances (yay!), and I was surprised by a keynote
acceptance. I ended up speaking at ONS Europe in
Amsterdam in September, and KubeCon NA in December. The ONS talk wasn&amp;rsquo;t
recorded, but it was also more of a practice run of the content I would finalize
for KubeCon NA. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t squeeze in VelocityConf NYC into my schedule, and was
sad to miss it (but I was having fun in Hong Kong instead). Also I started to
receive pointed questions about whether I could really code if I&amp;rsquo;m constantly
speaking/travelling :). And to be fair, I care a LOT about the quality of my
slides, and it is time consuming for me to make them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I was most terrified about was standing up there and saying something
universally Wrong or Bad. But people were engaged. There was note-taking,
picture-taking, &amp;ldquo;aha&amp;rdquo;s, and a lot of followup discussion both in person and on
twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;pure-img&#34; src=&#34;../img/github_work_2018.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;img class=&#34;pure-img&#34; src=&#34;img/github_personal_2018.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also attended a few meetups and conferences, my favorite of which was Building
Upwards by Vicki Cheung at Lyft. I loved listening to and chatting with women
and non-binary folk about infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
