<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Melanie Cebula&#39;s Blog</title>
		<link>https://melaniecebula.github.io/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Melanie Cebula&#39;s Blog</description>
		<generator>Hugo 0.53 -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en</language>
		<managingEditor>melaniecebula.bass@gmail.com (Melanie Cebula)</managingEditor>
		<webMaster>melaniecebula.bass@gmail.com (Melanie Cebula)</webMaster>
		<copyright>Melanie Cebula — All rights reserved.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 08:42:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://melaniecebula.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Starting a Blog and 2018 in Review</title>
			<link>https://melaniecebula.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 08:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
			<author>melaniecebula.bass@gmail.com (Melanie Cebula)</author>
			<guid>https://melaniecebula.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;In 2018 I decided to engage more with the larger technical community. I had a
few goals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speak at more technical conferences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage with other people/companies on twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start a technical blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to more open source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attend more events aimed at women/non-binary folks (and maybe organize one!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speak at more technical conferences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I
wanted to speak at a technical conference, but I had zero experience finding
conferences, filling out
abstracts, and submitting before CFPs close. I gave a first talk at FutureStack 2017,
but that was a bit different since it was a vendor conference and Airbnb was
invited to speak there. Also a manager signed me up before telling me about it
(thanks Joey!), so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t planned. So I started submitting proposals in the
middle of summer 2018. I got a
rejection, and three acceptances (yay!), and I was surprised by a keynote
acceptance. I ended up speaking at ONS Europe in
Amsterdam in September, and KubeCon NA in December. The ONS talk wasn&amp;rsquo;t
recorded, but it was also more of a practice run of the content I would finalize
for KubeCon NA. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t squeeze in VelocityConf NYC into my schedule, and was
sad to miss it (but I was having fun in Hong Kong instead). I love giving talks,
but they&amp;rsquo;re time consuming for me. In addition to practicing the presentation, I
spend a lot of hours drafting content and finalizing the slides. I spent even
more time polishing my KubeCon slides, because I knew a lot of people would see
it :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I was most terrified about was standing up there and saying something
universally Wrong or Bad. But people were engaged. There was note-taking,
picture-taking, &amp;ldquo;aha&amp;rdquo;s, and a lot of followup discussion both in person and on
twitter. What I loved most was meeting with people and other companies and
comparing/constrasting how we&amp;rsquo;ve tried to solve different problems. And there
are a lot of problems when you completely change your infrastructure to
Kubernetes. I walked away with a treasure trove of notes and ideas to share with
our infra teams, and feel re-energized about many of the technical and
organizational problems we&amp;rsquo;ve been facing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;status: super success!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engage with other people/companies on twitter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started picking up my twitter game shortly before the conferences. I put my
twitter handle on all my slides too :). I got a TON of engagement from KubeCon. I
went from ~400 to ~1000 followers, and finally feel engaged on the platform.
It&amp;rsquo;s a great way to see where things are going in infra in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;status: success&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start a technical blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I started setting up this blog on December 30th. I waffled a bit on how to
setup it up, but settled for using hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;status: kinda?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contribute to more open source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set up kubernetes locally and commented on and tried to work on an issue. Liz
Frost gave me a lot of 1:1 help reproing the issue. But the issue was too hard
for me to complete on a compressed timeframe at KubeCon :). So I&amp;rsquo;ll have to pick
this up later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was an uptick on open source contributions from Airbnb engineers in 2018
(My coworker Ramya found a scheduler bug related to balancing pods across
availability zones, and her fix will be in 1.14!!), and we&amp;rsquo;ll likely make more
contributions in 2019. For example, I know our Continuous Integration team is looking at current
open source image building solutions, and our Continuous Delivery team is
looking at moving us to Spinnaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;status: failure, I can do better!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attend more events aimed at women/non-binary folks (and maybe organize one!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also attended a few meetups and conferences, my favorite of which was Building
Upwards by Vicki Cheung at Lyft. I loved listening to and chatting with women
and non-binary folk about infrastructure. I wanted to plan one of these for late
2018 at Airbnb HQ, but we&amp;rsquo;re pushing it to 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;status: mostly success&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Contributions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I did a lot of coding in 2018 at work:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://melaniecebula.github.io/img/github_work_2018.png&#34; alt=&#34;work github&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the darker green boxes were actually automated refactors of 100+
services (now you can run refactors as a bot user to not mess with your
contributions if you&amp;rsquo;d like).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Highlights / Lowlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lowlights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spectre/Meltdown fallout continued into January (we also experience peak load in early January&amp;ndash; fun!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This one guy in PR kept trying to stop me from speaking and was super rude about it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unexpected and sudden departure of two close teammates :(&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imposter syndrome was a bitch, again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People trying to get me to debug stuff by implying an issue is somehow my fault (just ask nicely and I&amp;rsquo;m usually happy to jump on an issue, I actually enjoy debugging)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My project (new way of configuring and managing services) became general access for new services in April&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My project (streamlined way of migrating existing services to the new way) became general access in November&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leadership of different engineering groups signed off on migrating their services!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business trips to Dublin, Amsterdam, Portland, and Seattle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got promoted to senior software engineer! (well technically, from software engineer to software engineer since we use levels)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got to work all over infra this year (service discovery/networking, CI/CD, developer tooling, security, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker training and keynote at KubeCon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CEO and CTO know my project :). The project does have a hype name and catchphrase, which always helps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked on a lot of interesting problems this year, and look forward to sharing
my solutions now that the blog is up!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
